<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>domain-adaptation on Researcher profile</title>
    <link>https://wmkouw.github.io/tags/domain-adaptation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in domain-adaptation on Researcher profile</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 12:19:17 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://wmkouw.github.io/tags/domain-adaptation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The problem of domain adaptation in machine learning</title>
      <link>https://wmkouw.github.io/post/domain_adaptation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 12:19:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wmkouw.github.io/post/domain_adaptation/</guid>
      <description>Intelligent systems are deployed for a wide array of tasks, such as diagnosing patients, recognizing faces or translating texts [1]. They are called &amp;ldquo;intelligent&amp;rdquo; because these machines are not specifically programmed to perform the task. Instead, they learn to do their job from a &amp;ldquo;training set&amp;rdquo; of examples. For example, the system might be told to diagnose heart disease in patients based on biometrics such as age and cholesterol level. These biometrics vary across people and there is no fixed rule to form a diagnosis (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A review of single-source unsupervised domain adaptation</title>
      <link>https://wmkouw.github.io/publication/review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 16:13:59 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wmkouw.github.io/publication/review/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An introduction to domain adaptation and transfer learning</title>
      <link>https://wmkouw.github.io/publication/tr_introda/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 14:46:06 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wmkouw.github.io/publication/tr_introda/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Target contrastive pessimistic discriminant analysis</title>
      <link>https://wmkouw.github.io/publication/tcpr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 08:45:35 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wmkouw.github.io/publication/tcpr/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LibTLDA</title>
      <link>https://wmkouw.github.io/project/libtlda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 19:06:57 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wmkouw.github.io/project/libtlda/</guid>
      <description>LibTLDA is a library of classifiers designed for domain adaptation and transfer learning, available in Matlab and Python. It started out as the collection of classifiers that I implemented during my PhD, but is now being expanded with more methods and algorithms.
Installation has been made easy, and there are demos to help you get started. Coders familiar with sci-kit will find it easy to pick up.
More information is available on its documentation page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Target contrastive estimator for robust domain adaptation</title>
      <link>https://wmkouw.github.io/talk/nvphbv2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 19:18:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wmkouw.github.io/talk/nvphbv2016/</guid>
      <description>NVPHBV is the Dutch Society for Pattern Recognition and Image Processing. During their meetings, researchers from the Netherlands have a chance to present some of their work and catch up on developments in their fields.
I presented my work on a robust estimator for linear discriminant analysis in domain-adaptive machine learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TCR</title>
      <link>https://wmkouw.github.io/project/tcpr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 18:05:01 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wmkouw.github.io/project/tcpr/</guid>
      <description>In domain adaptation, one is always required to make assumptions on how the two domains relate to each other. However, depending on the domain dissimilarity, these assumptions can be quite strong. Furthermore, they are often hard to support, even with labeled target samples. Unfortunately, when an assumption is invalid, the classifier can adapt itself in ways that are detrimental to performance. Therefore, in practice, it can be hard to predict whether a domain-adaptive classifier will perform well for a given problem setting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feature-level domain adaptation</title>
      <link>https://wmkouw.github.io/talk/ictopen2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2016 10:44:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wmkouw.github.io/talk/ictopen2016/</guid>
      <description>ICT.OPEN is the Dutch national conference for computer science in general. Researchers from various universities and companies present their work along different tracks.
I presented my first project, on feature-level domain adaptation, in the Natural Artificial Intelligence track.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FLDA</title>
      <link>https://wmkouw.github.io/project/flda/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 18:05:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wmkouw.github.io/project/flda/</guid>
      <description>Suppose that data is collected according to a set of features, such as blood pressure in clinical research or word frequencies in natural language processing. Now, in the source domain, all these features are measured, while in the target domain, some values are missing or absent (i.e. words are not used in the target context). In this case, one could capture the relationship between the domains using a probabilistic model, an approach we have called feature-level domain adaptation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feature absence regularization for domain-adaptive learning</title>
      <link>https://wmkouw.github.io/talk/snn2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2015 11:00:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wmkouw.github.io/talk/snn2015/</guid>
      <description>SNN organized a one day symposium entitled Intelligent Machines, where an overview of recent developments was presented. The meeting aimed to establish a dialogue and to build connections between academic research, industry and public institutions in the Netherlands.
I presented my preliminary work on incorporating transfer models in domain-adaptive classifiers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>