<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Courses | Wouter M. Kouw</title>
    <link>https://wmkouw.github.io/teaching/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://wmkouw.github.io/teaching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Courses</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://wmkouw.github.io/media/icon_hu16822585919008292112.png</url>
      <title>Courses</title>
      <link>https://wmkouw.github.io/teaching/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>TU/e 5EZC0</title>
      <link>https://wmkouw.github.io/teaching/tue-5ezc0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wmkouw.github.io/teaching/tue-5ezc0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://canvas.tue.nl/courses/30244&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;5EZC0 Math 3 - Probability &amp;amp; Statistics&lt;/a&gt; is a core Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s course in the Electrical Engineering Bachelor Program of the TU Eindhoven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mathematics is the foundation upon which engineering sciences are built and is at the core of disciplines that drive technological developments and innovations in the digital age. This course introduces students to the mathematics of probability and statistics, indispensable in the fields of communication, signal processing, control, and machine learning, among others. The student will learn about:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Random experiments and probability models (set theory, probability axioms, conditional probability, independence).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discrete random variables (probability mass function, cumulative distribution function, families of discrete random variables, functions of random
variables, expectation, variance).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continuous random variables (probability density function, cumulative distribution function, families of continuous random variables, Gaussian
random variables).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiple (two) random variables (joint distributions, marginal distributions, conditional distributions, covariance, correlation, independence,
Bivariate Gaussian random vectors).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stochastic processes (definitions, stationary processes, Poisson process, Gaussian process).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Statistical inference (posterior distribution, MAP rule, least mean squares estimation).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TU/e 5XIF0</title>
      <link>https://wmkouw.github.io/teaching/tue-5xif0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wmkouw.github.io/teaching/tue-5xif0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://canvas.tue.nl/courses/23398&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;5XIF0 Neuro Computation&lt;/a&gt; is an elective course in the Electrical Engineering Bachelor Program of the TU Eindhoven and a core course in the Neuro System Design package of the Neuro Engineering track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The human brain and other biological neural systems are incredibly efficient at processing information, can handle complex and noisy data inputs, learn quickly, and adapt to new situations while operating in a highly parallel and distributed manner. This is very different than the current artificial intelligence approach, which requires too much power and does not scale. Thus, efforts are underway to develop artificial neural networks that can approach the efficiency and effectiveness of biological neural systems. These efforts include research in neurocomputing and include the development of new theories, methods, and algorithms in designing more specialized &amp;rsquo;neuromorphic&amp;rsquo; hardware architectures that support bio-inspired neural networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 5XIF0 Neuro Computation you will have the opportunity to learn the computational properties of neurobiological systems and you will learn to design spiking neural networks using mixed-signal &amp;ldquo;neuromorphic&amp;rdquo; electronic circuits. Similar to their biological counterparts, these neuromorphic implementations operate in continuous time in a massively parallel way, are extremely efficient, and represent the third generation of neural networks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TU/e 5XSL0</title>
      <link>https://wmkouw.github.io/teaching/tue-5xsl0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wmkouw.github.io/teaching/tue-5xsl0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://canvas.tue.nl/courses/16579&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;5XSL0 Fundamentals of Machine Learning&lt;/a&gt; (BMLIP) is an elective course in the Electrical Engineering Bachelor Program of the TU Eindhoven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We live in the age of data. The amount of data has been increasing at an exponential rate over the last decades and is expected to continue. Not only is the volume of the data larger than ever before, also the variety in types of data is consistently growing. Due to the enormous progress in sensor technology, we can measure more than ever before. The vast amounts of heterogeneous data harbor useful information that can help in e.g. clinical decision-making, predictive maintenance and visual object detection. However, due to its growing volume and complexity, it becomes increasingly harder for humans to extract this information by manually analyzing the patterns in the data. Machine learning is a subfield of Artificial Intelligence (AI) that focuses on building mathematical models that can extract information from data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course aims to offer a solid theoretical basis for modern machine learning methods. It will teach students the mathematical foundations of machine learning, introduce a number of elementary techniques and discuss methods for evaluation of model performance. These concepts are the fundamental building blocks of modern AI approaches and offer important insights.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TU/e 5SSD0</title>
      <link>https://wmkouw.github.io/teaching/tue-5ssd0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wmkouw.github.io/teaching/tue-5ssd0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://biaslab.github.io/teaching/bmlip/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;5SSD0 Bayesian Machine Learning &amp;amp; Information Processing&lt;/a&gt; (BMLIP) is a course in the Electrical Engineering Master programme of TU Eindhoven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BMLIP covers the fundamentals of the Bayesian (i.e., probabilistic) approach to machine learning and information processing systems. Firstly, we discuss many useful models including common regression and classification methods, Gaussian mixture models, hidden Markov models and Kalman filters. Secondly, we teach Expectation-Maximization (EM), Variational Bayes (VB) and Variational Message Passing (VMP). Lastly, we discuss intelligent agents that learn purposeful behavior from interactions with their environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I teach the lectures on Probabilistic Programming, where students write software for automatic inference in probabilistic models.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
