<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notes on Researcher profile</title>
    <link>https://wmkouw.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Notes on Researcher profile</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://wmkouw.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Are all practical problems interesting?</title>
      <link>https://wmkouw.github.io/post/practical_problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 16:58:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wmkouw.github.io/post/practical_problems/</guid>
      <description>On many occasions, I have seen researchers being recommended to work on practical problems. For example, instead of looking for a neural network architecture that has never been proposed before, design a model for tracking a particular stage of cancer development. A first argument is that this makes a stronger impact on clinical research and society. The applied researcher would be happy, but a theorist would argue that the result is too specific to generalize to other diseases, and is therefore less interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is domain-adaptive machine learning?</title>
      <link>https://wmkouw.github.io/post/domain_adaptation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 12:19:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wmkouw.github.io/post/domain_adaptation/</guid>
      <description>Intelligent systems are deployed for a wide array of tasks, such as diagnosing patients, recognizing faces or translating texts [1]. They are called &amp;ldquo;intelligent&amp;rdquo; because these machines are not specifically programmed to perform the task. Instead, they learn to do their job from a &amp;ldquo;training set&amp;rdquo; of examples. For example, the system might be told to diagnose heart disease in patients based on biometrics such as age and cholesterol level. These biometrics vary across people and there is no fixed rule to form a diagnosis (e.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>