<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Researcher profile</title>
    <link>https://wmkouw.github.io/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Researcher profile</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://wmkouw.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>LibTLDA</title>
      <link>https://wmkouw.github.io/project/libtlda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 19:06:57 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wmkouw.github.io/project/libtlda/</guid>
      <description>LibTLDA is a library of classifiers designed for domain adaptation and transfer learning, available in Matlab and Python. It started out as the collection of classifiers that I implemented during my PhD, but is now being expanded with more methods and algorithms.
Installation has been made easy, and there are demos to help you get started. Coders familiar with sci-kit will find it easy to employ.
More information is available on its github page and its documentation page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EviDENce</title>
      <link>https://wmkouw.github.io/project/evidence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 19:11:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wmkouw.github.io/project/evidence/</guid>
      <description>For my second project at the Netherlands eScience Center, I worked on a collaboration project between Susan Hogervorst at the Open University, Marieke van Erp at the Digital Humanities Lab of the KNAW, and Hennie Brugman of the Meertens Institute, along with my partner engineer Martine de Vos.
Much of our historical knowledge is based on oral or written accounts of eyewitnesses, particularly in cases of war and mass violence, when regular ways of documentation and record keeping are often absent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>boneCTCNN</title>
      <link>https://wmkouw.github.io/project/mfs-bonecnn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 19:12:54 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wmkouw.github.io/project/mfs-bonecnn/</guid>
      <description>My first project at the Netherlands eScience Center was with the winner of the Young eScientist Award 2016, dr. Maureen van Eijnatten. She worked at the 3D Innovation Lab under the department of Maxillo-Facial Surgery at the Vrije Universiteit medical center (VUmc), together with PhD student Jordi Minnema and medical engineer Niels Liberton.
During the project, we developed a method for automatically detecting bone tissue in medical CT-scanner images. This method consisted of an artificial neural network, called a convolutional neural network (CNN), which looks at individual voxels in the image plus their surroundings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IWcrossval</title>
      <link>https://wmkouw.github.io/project/iwcv/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 17:35:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wmkouw.github.io/project/iwcv/</guid>
      <description>During my PhD, I got interested in the question:
&amp;ldquo;How should you do cross-validation when facing shifts in your covariates and you have no labels for your target data?&amp;rdquo;
Sugiyama&amp;rsquo;s group has worked on this question extensively, and proposes a technique called &amp;ldquo;importance-weighted cross-validation&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;ve used this estimator before, but found that it behaves unusually in certain cases. That led me to start investigating the difference between the importance-weighted source risk estimator and the target risk estimator in greater detail.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>